<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Indonesian Heroes</string>

    <string name="heroes_name">Hero Name</string>
    <string name="desc">Description</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="details">&#8230;</string>
    <string name="Birthdate">Birthdate</string>
    <string name="Birthplace">Origin</string>
    <string name="self_name">Ricky Fadel M</string>
    <string name="self_bangkit_mail">a169dsx2750@bangkit.academy</string>
    <string name="self_img">https://rickyslash.my.id/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/sm-rickyslash-1-c-480x480.jpg</string>

    <string-array name="data_name">
        <item>Ahmad Dahlan</item>
        <item>Ahmad Yani</item>
        <item>Sutomo</item>
        <item>Gatot Soebroto</item>
        <item>Ki Hadjar Dewantara</item>
        <item>Mohammad Hatta</item>
        <item>Soedirman</item>
        <item>Soekarno</item>
        <item>Soepomo</item>
        <item>Tan Malaka</item>
        <item>B.J. Habibie</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="data_description">
        <item>"Ahmad Dahlan (1868–1923) was an Indonesian Islamic reformer and founder of Muhammadiyah, one of the largest Muslim organizations in Indonesia. Born in Yogyakarta, he received a traditional Islamic education and later studied at the Dutch–run STOVIA medical school. Despite his medical training, Dahlan's focus shifted to religious education and reform. He became a vocal advocate for Islamic modernism, which aimed to reconcile Islamic teachings with modern knowledge and values, and believed that Islamic education was crucial for the advancement of the Muslim community.\n\nIn 1912, Dahlan founded Muhammadiyah, which aimed to promote a purer and more authentic practice of Islam and provide education and social welfare to Muslims in Indonesia. The organization grew rapidly and has since become a significant force in Indonesian politics and society, with millions of members and a network of schools, hospitals, and social programs. Ahmad Dahlan's legacy as a religious and social reformer continues to inspire many in Indonesia and beyond."</item>
        <item>"Ahmad Yani (1922–1965) was an Indonesian army general and a hero of the Indonesian National Revolution. Born in Purworejo, Central Java, he joined the Dutch colonial army in 1940 and later fought for Indonesian independence in the 1940s. After independence, he served in various military positions, including as the commander of the army's strategic reserve in the late 1950s and early 1960s.\n\nIn 1965, Yani played a prominent role in the Indonesian political crisis that led to the fall of President Sukarno and the rise of General Suharto. Yani was a vocal critic of Sukarno's policies and had called for the removal of communist elements from the government and military. However, on the night of October 1, 1965, Yani was kidnapped and assassinated by a group of soldiers loyal to Sukarno. His death marked the beginning of a period of political violence and repression in Indonesia, which led to the deaths of hundreds of thousands of people. Ahmad Yani is remembered as a national hero and a symbol of the struggle for Indonesian independence and democracy."</item>
        <item>"Sutomo, also known as Bung Tomo (1920–1981), was an Indonesian nationalist and independence activist. Born in Surabaya, East Java, he became involved in the Indonesian Nationalist Party (PNI) and the youth movement in the 1940s. During the Indonesian National Revolution, Sutomo became a prominent figure in the Battle of Surabaya, leading a group of young fighters against British and Dutch colonial forces. He became known for his fiery speeches and his ability to mobilize the people of Surabaya in the fight for independence.\n\nAfter independence, Sutomo continued to be involved in politics, serving as a member of parliament and as the Minister of Labor and Manpower in the 1950s and 1960s. He was also known for his advocacy for social justice, particularly for the rights of workers and peasants. Sutomo remained a popular figure among Indonesians, particularly in East Java, where he was seen as a hero of the independence struggle. His legacy as a nationalist and advocate for social justice continues to inspire many in Indonesia today."</item>
        <item>"Gatot Soebroto (1907–1962) was an Indonesian military leader and one of the most respected figures in the Indonesian Armed Forces. Born in Banyumas, he joined the Dutch colonial army in 1933 and later fought for Indonesian independence in the 1940s. After independence, he continued to serve in the military and held various high–ranking positions, including as the commander of the Army Strategic Reserve Command (Kostrad) in the 1950s and early 1960s.\n\nGatot was known for his leadership and his commitment to modernizing and professionalizing the Indonesian military. He played a key role in the suppression of the PRRI/Permesta rebellion in Sumatra and Sulawesi in the 1950s, which threatened to destabilize the young Indonesian republic. Gatot died in a plane crash in 1962, along with President Sukarno's wife and several other high–ranking officials. He is remembered as a hero of the Indonesian independence struggle and a symbol of the country's military might and national unity. The Gatot Soebroto Army Hospital in Jakarta, one of the largest military hospitals in Southeast Asia, is named in his honor."</item>
        <item>"Raden Mas Soewardi Soerjaningrat (1889–1959), also known as Ki Hajar Dewantara, was an Indonesian educator, writer, and independence activist. Born in Yogyakarta, he was the son of a noble family and received a Dutch-style education in his youth. However, he became disillusioned with colonial rule and became involved in the Indonesian nationalist movement in the early 1900s.\n\nKi Hajar Dewantara is best known for his contributions to the development of education in Indonesia. He believed that education should be based on the principles of national identity, social justice, and cultural pluralism. In 1913, he founded the first nationalistic school in Indonesia, Taman Siswa, which emphasized the importance of learning traditional Javanese culture alongside modern education. He also played a key role in the establishment of the Indonesian Teachers' Association and was a strong advocate for the use of the Indonesian language in education. Ki Hajar Dewantara is remembered as a national hero and an important figure in the history of Indonesian education and culture. The Indonesian Ministry of Education and Culture awards the Ki Hajar Dewantara Award to outstanding educators in his honor."</item>
        <item>"Drs. H. Mohammad Hatta (1902–1980) was an Indonesian nationalist leader and statesman who played a key role in the country's struggle for independence from Dutch colonial rule. Born in West Sumatra, he received his education in the Netherlands, where he became involved in the Indonesian nationalist movement. Along with Sukarno, he was one of the leading figures in the struggle for independence and served as the first Vice President of Indonesia after independence was achieved in 1945.\n\nHatta was known for his political and economic expertise, and played a key role in the development of Indonesia's economic policies during his time in office. He was also a prominent advocate for democracy and social justice, and was a strong supporter of education and the arts. Hatta is remembered as a national hero in Indonesia, and his legacy as a leader and statesman is still celebrated today."</item>
        <item>"Sudirman, also known as General Sudirman, was an Indonesian military leader and national hero who played a significant role in the country's fight for independence from Dutch colonial rule. Born on January 24, 1916, in Purbalingga, Central Java, he was the youngest of nine siblings and grew up in a rural farming family. He joined the Indonesian National Army and was appointed as its commander-in-chief in 1945, leading the fight against the Dutch colonial forces. Despite facing numerous challenges, including a lack of weapons and equipment, Sudirman was able to inspire his troops and lead them to several decisive victories.\n\nSudirman's legacy as a national hero is celebrated in Indonesia, and his life serves as an inspiration for many. He was known for his courage, leadership, and dedication to the Indonesian people, and his contributions to the country's independence have earned him a place in the hearts of many Indonesians. Today, his image is often used as a symbol of the nation's struggle for freedom, and his name is attached to various public institutions, including an airport and a university."</item>
        <item>"Ir. H. Soekarno (1901–1970) was the first President of Indonesia and a prominent leader in the country's struggle for independence from Dutch colonial rule. Born in East Java, he studied engineering in the Netherlands before becoming involved in the Indonesian nationalist movement. Soekarno was known for his powerful oratory skills and charismatic leadership, and was a key figure in the establishment of the Republic of Indonesia in 1945.\n\nDuring his presidency, Soekarno was known for his strong commitment to Indonesian nationalism and his advocacy of a non-aligned foreign policy. He was also a prominent advocate for social justice and economic development, and introduced a number of ambitious policies aimed at modernizing Indonesia's economy and infrastructure. Despite his later political controversies, Soekarno is remembered as a national hero in Indonesia, and his legacy as a leader and statesman is still celebrated today."</item>
        <item>"Prof. Mr. Dr. Soepomo (1903–1958) was an Indonesian statesman and legal scholar who played a key role in the country's struggle for independence from Dutch colonial rule. Born in Central Java, he received his education in the Netherlands before becoming involved in the Indonesian nationalist movement. Soepomo was a prominent legal scholar and was known for his contributions to the development of Indonesia's legal system.\n\nDuring the 1940s, Soepomo played a key role in the negotiations with the Dutch colonial authorities that led to the establishment of the Republic of Indonesia. He also served as the country's first Minister of Justice and was a strong advocate for the rule of law and human rights. Soepomo is remembered as a national hero in Indonesia, and his legacy as a legal scholar and statesman is still celebrated today."</item>
        <item>"Tan Malaka (1897–1949) was an Indonesian nationalist and revolutionary leader who played a prominent role in the country's struggle for independence from Dutch colonial rule. Born in Sumatra, he was educated in the Netherlands and became involved in leftist politics in Europe. Upon his return to Indonesia in the early 1920s, he became a leading figure in the Indonesian nationalist movement and played a key role in the formation of the first political party in Indonesia, the Partai Persatuan Indonesia (PPI).\n\nTan Malaka was known for his revolutionary ideas and his critical analysis of colonialism and capitalism. He was a prolific writer and author of numerous books and articles on politics and economics. Although his views were controversial and sometimes led to conflict with other nationalist leaders, Tan Malaka is remembered as a national hero in Indonesia, and his legacy as a revolutionary and intellectual is still celebrated today."</item>
        <item>"B.J. Habibie was an Indonesian engineer and politician who was born in Parepare, South Sulawesi, Indonesia in 1936. He studied aviation and aerospace engineering in Germany and worked for the German aircraft manufacturer Messerschmitt-Bölkow-Blohm before returning to Indonesia in 1974 to work for the government. He became a key advisor to President Suharto and played a significant role in Indonesia's efforts to develop its aerospace industry.\n\nIn 1998, Habibie became Indonesia's president after Suharto's resignation. He promised to promote democracy and reform the country's economy, and his presidency was marked by several significant achievements, including the release of political prisoners and granting greater autonomy to the provinces. Habibie was also instrumental in creating a more open society in Indonesia, although his administration was also marked by controversies such as corruption allegations and economic turmoil. Despite these challenges, Habibie remains a respected figure in Indonesian politics and is remembered for his contributions to promoting democracy and modernization in the country."</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="data_birthplace">
        <item>Yogyakarta, DIY</item>
        <item>Purworejo, Jateng</item>
        <item>Surabaya, Jatim</item>
        <item>Banyumas, Central Java</item>
        <item>Pakualaman, DIY</item>
        <item>Bukittinggi, Sumbar</item>
        <item>Purbalingga, Jateng</item>
        <item>Blitar, Jatim</item>
        <item>Sukoharjo, Jateng</item>
        <item>Pandam Gadang , Sumbar</item>
        <item>Parepare, Sulsel</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="data_birthdate">
        <item>1 Aug 1868</item>
        <item>19 Jun 1922</item>
        <item>3 Oct 1920</item>
        <item>10 Oct 1907</item>
        <item>2 May 1889</item>
        <item>12 Aug 1902</item>
        <item>24 Jan 1916</item>
        <item>6 Jun 1901</item>
        <item>7 Jan 1903</item>
        <item>2 Jun 1897</item>
        <item>25 Jun 1936</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="data_photo">
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/87/Ahmad_Dahlan.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/3f/Ahmad_Yani.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/ed/Bung_Tomo.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/be/Col_Gatot_Subroto%2C_Kenang-Kenangan_Pada_Panglima_Besar_Letnan_Djenderal_Soedirman%2C_p27.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/3a/Ki_Hadjar_Dewantara_Mimbar_Umum_18_October_1949_p2.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/3b/VP_Hatta.jpg/330px-VP_Hatta.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e7/Sudirman.jpg/486px-Sudirman.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/01/Presiden_Sukarno.jpg/330px-Presiden_Sukarno.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a6/Supomo.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f7/TanMalaka_DariPendjara_ed3.jpg/330px-TanMalaka_DariPendjara_ed3.jpg</item>
        <item>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/2a/B._J._Habibie%2C_President_of_Indonesia_portrait.jpg/393px-B._J._Habibie%2C_President_of_Indonesia_portrait.jpg</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>